<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditation on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditation on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Observing Your Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/observing-your-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/observing-your-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You are right, Watson,&amp;rdquo; said he. &amp;ldquo;It does seem a most preposterous way of settling a dispute.&amp;quot;
  &amp;ldquo;Most preposterous!&amp;rdquo; I exclaimed, and then suddenly realizing how he had echoed the inmost thought of my soul, I sat up in my chair and stared at him in blank amazement&amp;rdquo; - Adventures of the Cardboard Box
 Sherlock Holmes might have been able to predict the thoughts of Dr. Watson but I have found out that predicting my own thoughts is enough of a challenge for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday Meditation</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/everyday-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/everyday-meditation/</guid>
      <description>Meditation sucks at first. It sucks badly for a long long time. It is SO bad, SO sucky. The harder you try the more you suck at it. But it is hubris to assume that you would naturally be an expert at it. I have been trying it on and off unsuccessfully for many years. Only now, thanks to the lockdown, I have finally been able to do it consistently and have started liking it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Meditation?</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/why-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/meditation/why-meditation/</guid>
      <description>An idea from psychology I really like is the four stages of competence. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt directly from Wikipedia:
   Unconscious incompetence. The individual does not understand or know how to do something and does not necessarily recognize the deficit. They may deny the usefulness of the skill. The individual must recognize their own incompetence, and the value of the new skill, before moving on to the next stage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
